https://www.cdrfoodlab.com/privacy-policy/

Distributors
Home Privacy Policy and personal data processing information Privacy Policy and personal data processing information
Information request form
Newsletter subscription
Marketing/Profiling Cookies
Information request form – Processing of personal data
Pursuant to Regulation (EU) 2016/679, this page describes the methods of processing of personal data communicated by the person concerned through the “Contacts” form present on all pages of the website www.cdrfoodlab.com.
This information does not concern other sites, pages or online services that can be reached via hypertext links that may be published on our website.
Data controller
The data controller is CDR s.r.l. with headquarters in Via degli Artigiani, 6 – 50055 Ginestra Fiorentina (FI).
E-mail cdr@cdr-mediared.it
Data protection officer
CDR s.r.l does not require the figure of the Data Protection Manager pursuant to art. 37 of the EU Regulation 679/2016.
Purpose, legal basis and mandatory or optional nature of the processing
The Personal Data provided by the interested party by completing the “Contact” form will be processed by the Data Controller for the purpose of managing requests (merely for example to respond to requests for information, etc.).
The personal data subject to processing is solely that provided by the data subject when sending messages via the Form.
The provision of personal data (company, first name, surname, mobile number, e-mail and message) is optional. In the absence of such transfer, the Data Controller will not be able to respond to the requests received.
Regarding the use of cookies by the Site, please refer to the “Cookie Policy” accessible via the “Privacy” link in all sections of the Site.
Types of data processed and purpose of processing
Data communicated by the user
The personal data provided directly by the interested party, by filling in the “Contacts” form, involves acquisition of the same data.
Personal data processing method
The data collected is processed using IT tools and only on a residual basis using paper-based methods.
For the processing of data related to the services of the website the Data Controller uses servers located within the European territory and IT systems located at the Data Controller’s headquarters. Its transfer abroad is not envisaged.
Adequate technical and organisational measures are taken to guarantee an adequate level of security and the prevent the loss of data, illicit or incorrect uses and unauthorised accesses.
The data provided directly by the interested party is kept for the entire duration of the contractual relationship and according to legal obligations.
Data recipients
Your data may be communicated to, or may become known to, the employees or collaborators of our company, expressly designated by us as “authorised to process” and /or appointed as “external processing manager” (e.g. the provider of the web platform development and maintenance services).
Rights of interested parties.
Interested parties have the right to obtain from Conceria Tempesti Spa access to personal data in the cases provided for, and also the correction or deletion of the same or the limitation of the processing that concerns them or to object to the processing and portability of data (arts. 15 and following of the Regulation).
Requests should be sent to cdr@cdr-mediared.it
Right to complain
Interested parties who believe that the processing of personal data referring to them carried out through this site is in violation of the provisions of the Regulation may lodge a complaint with the Guarantor, as provided for by art. 77 of the same Regulation, or take the appropriate legal action (art. 79 of the Regulation).
Newsletter subscription – Processing of personal data
The CDR Srl Newsletter (https://www.cdrfoodlab.com) is distributed via e-mail – automatically and free of charge – to those persons who expressly request to receive it, by filling in the form accessible on all the pages of our website and authorising CDR Srl to the processing of personal data.
The data provided will be used with IT and telematic tools for the sole purpose of providing the requested service and, for this reason, will be kept exclusively for the period during which it is active.
The legal basis of this processing is to be found in the consent of the interested party.
The data controller is CDR Srl , with headquarters in Via degli Artigiani, 6 – 50055 Ginestra Fiorentina (FI).
Your data may be communicated, or it may come to the knowledge of the employees or collaborators of our company, expressly appointed by us as “designated/authorised data processors” and / or of the “external processing manager” (e.g. for site technological maintenance requirements).
Interested parties have the right to obtain from CDR Srl , in the cases provided, access to personal data and the correction or deletion of the same, limitation of the processing that concerns them or may object to the processing (arts. 15 and following of the Regulation).
Requests should be sent to the e-mail: privacy@cdr-mediared.it
Interested parties who believe that the processing of their personal data carried out through this service is in violation of the provisions of the Regulation may lodge a complaint with the Guarantor, as provided for by art. 77 of the same Regulation, or may take the appropriate legal action (art. 79 of the Regulation).
Service cancellation
To stop receiving the newsletter, click on “Unsubscribe from the Newsletter” at the bottom of every e-mail you receive.
In case of technical problems, it is possible to send an e-mail notification to: privacy@cdr-mediared.it
Marketing/Profiling Cookies
Privacy Disclaimer
This page describes how the website www.cdrfoodlab.com owned by CDR S.r.l. as Data Controller is managed in relation to the processing of personal data of users who consult it and as such represents a Privacy Disclaimer.
The Data Controller takes very seriously the protection and protection of the personal data of its users. The processing is based on the principles of correctness, lawfulness, transparency and protection of confidentiality in compliance with Legislative Decree 196/2003 and with the European Regulation 2016/679 (hereafter GDPR 2016/679).
1. Data Controller
The data controller is CDR srl, with headquarters in Via degli Artigiani, 6 – Ginestra Fiorentina 50055 Lastra a Signa – Florence
2. Data processing address
The processings linked to the services of this website take place at the headquarters of CDR srl and are only handled by the technical staff in charge of processing. The server that hosts www.cdrfoodlab.com, owned by CDR S.r.l., is located in housing at Aste Giudiziarie Inlinea S.p.A., with registered office at via delle Grazie 5, 57125, Livorno. No data deriving from the web service is disseminated. The personal data provided by users who sent requests is used only to perform the service or provision requested.
3. Types of data processed
Browsing data
During normal operation, the IT systems and software procedures involved in operation of this portal collect certain personal data, the transmission of which is implicit in the use of Internet communication protocols.
This is information that is not collected to be associated with identified interested parties but which, by its very nature, could, through processing and association with data held by third parties, allow users to be identified.
This category of data includes IP addresses or domain names of the computers used by users who connect to the website, the addresses in the Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) notation of the requested resources, the time of the request, the method used to submit the request to the server, the size of the file obtained in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the response given by the server (success, error, etc.) and other parameters relating to the operating system and to the user’s IT environment.
This data is used for the sole purpose of obtaining anonymous statistical information on the use of the website and to check its correct functioning and is deleted immediately after processing. The data could be used to ascertain responsibility in case of hypothetical computer crimes against the website.
Cookies
Our website uses cookies. By browsing our websites and accepting the terms of this disclaimer, you are consenting to the use of cookies in accordance with the terms and conditions of the information itself.
What are cookies
Cookies are small data files that the websites visited by the user send to their terminal or device, where they can be deleted at the end of each work session or stored to be re-transmitted to the same websites upon subsequent visit of the same user. Cookies allow a website to recognise the user’s device, to track their browsing through the different pages of the website and to identify users who visit the website again.
There are different types of cookies:
Technical cookies that include:
Browsing and session cookies that guarantee normal browsing on the website (e.g. they allow authentication for access to restricted areas);
Functionality cookies that make browsing easier for the user by storing the choices made, e.g. language chosen);
Analytical cookies that are used to process aggregate statistical analysis on how users browse the website, the number of pages visited, the number of clicks made on a page, etc.
Profiling cookies that allow the creation of profiles related to the tastes, choices and propensities expressed by the user during browsing and which are subsequently used to send advertising messages in line with their preferences.
The profiling cookies used on this website are exclusively those of third parties
Third-Party Cookies
In the course of browsing the website, users may receive cookies from different websites or from web servers (so-called “third-party” cookies) on their terminals: this happens because the website may contain elements such as, for example, images, maps, sounds and specific links to web pages of other domains that reside on servers other than the one on which the requested page is located. In other words, these cookies are set directly by managers of websites or servers other than those of the website.
These cookies can be sent to the user’s browser by third-party companies directly from their websites which can be accessed by browsing from the Foodlab Website. In such cases, Foodlab is not involved in the operation of these cookies, the sending of which is the responsibility of such third-party companies. This is in fact clarified by the Privacy Guarantor: “The obligation to inform the user about the use of cookies and to possibly acquire prior consent lies with the operator of the website that uses them, as the data controller. If a website also allows the transmission of “third-party” cookies, the information and the acquisition of consent are normally the responsibility of the third party. The user must be adequately informed, albeit with the simplified procedures provided for by law, when accessing the website that allows the storage of third-party cookies, or when accessing the contents provided by third parties and in any event before cookies are downloaded onto their terminal”.
Precisely for the purpose of transparency of the information requested from the operators of the “first-party website” (i.e. the website as managed by Foodlab”) where “third-party cookies” operate, we inform you that the following third-party cookies are operational on the website:
Google Analytics
Thus website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies which are text files placed on your computer to allow the website to analyse how users use the website. The information generated by the cookies about your use of the website (including your anonymous IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of examining your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.
This cookie is not a tool that we own. For further information it is therefore possible to consult the information provided by Google at the following address:
https://policies.google.com/privacy
If you would prefer Google Analytics not to use the data collected in any way, you can:
use anonymous browsing (Do Not Track potion) from your browser. To learn how to activate the option on the main search engines click on the browser that uses Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Mozzilla Firefox or Apple Safari.
You can refuse to use cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, but doing so may impede the ability to use all the functions of this website. By browsing the pages of the website, you are consenting to the processing of data by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.
You can prevent Google from detecting a cookie that is generated and linked to its use of this website (including your IP address) by downloading and installing this browser plugin: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en
Embedded Contents
cdrfoodlab.com sometimes uses YouTube videos, social media content on Twitter, Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn and, in general, elements based on the possible embeddable content of other platforms. cdrfoodlab.com cannot control cookies that these third-party websites provide and for this reason it is advisable to obtain information directly from each third party to ensure greater control over these cookies. Below are a number of links that are useful for the privacy cookies of the cited third parties:
Facebook https://www.facebook.com/help/cookies/
Twitter https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en
Youtube https://www.google.it/intl/it/policies/privacy/
Google+ https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types
LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy
CrazyEgg
cdrfoodlab.com occasionally uses these cookies to optimise the web pages of its website by analysing the movements of users anonymously within the website. For further information on the policy of CrazyEgg visit the link https://www.crazyegg.com/privacy. Instead, to disable all the cookies of CrazyEgg use the following link https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out
HotJar
cdrfoodlab.com occasionally uses these cookies to optimise the web pages of its website by analysing the movements of users anonymously within the website. For further information on the policy of HotJar visit the link https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy/. For a complete overview on HotJar Compliance, Legal & Security you can follow the link https://help.hotjar.com/hc/en-us/categories/360003405813-Compliance-Legal-Security-
DoubleClick
cdrfoodlab.com, in order to show the banners on the pages, make use of the DoubleClick third-party service. The service is used in a basic way and therefore without any type of behavioural analysis. For further information on the cookies in question, use the following link https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/.
Mautic
cdrfoodlab.com uses these cookies to monitor visitors on websites. The purpose is to personalize the choices and preferences of the user with regards to ads to be displayed and to make the navigation of the site more engaging for the user. For more information on Mautic’s policies https://www.mautic.org/privacy-policy
Cookie Block/Management
It is possible to configure your browser to accept all cookies, to reject them all or to be notified when the cookie is set. Each browser is different and so it is advisable to check the procedures in the browser guide to change your cookie preferences.
E.g.:
Delete/disable cookies with Firefox: http://support.mozilla.com/it/kb/Eliminare%20i%20cookie
Delete/disable cookies with Edge: https://support.microsoft.com/it-it/help/4027947/windows-delete-cookies
Delete/disable cookies with Chrome: http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=it&answer=95647
Data provided voluntarily
Apart from what is specified for the browsing data necessary to implement the computer and data protocols, the provision of personal data by users is free and optional, although functional to the provision of certain services: in these cases, therefore, the failure to provide data may compromise or make it impossible to provide the service.
Personal data that voluntarily interacts with the website, conferred for the obtaining of certain services (registration with the website, registration for events/competitions with prizes, requests for information, the sending of e-mails) is only used to perform the service or provision requested and is only communicated to third parties if this is strictly necessary for implementation of the service.
The provision of data for direct marketing and/or profiling purposes is optional and the user is free to provide their consent for such processing.
This consent may be revoked at any time by going to the website and clicking on the appropriate link in the foot of the “Cookie Policy” website.
For the processing of personal data that consists of sending e-mail newsletters as well as informative material relating to the services offered by the data controller, consent can be revoked by clicking on the link “Unsubscribe” at the bottom of each e-mail.
Children under 16 may not provide personal data. The Data Controller will not in no way be responsible for any false statements that may be provided by a minor and, in any case, if the former ascertains the falsity of the statements, any personal data of any material acquired will immediately be deleted. The Data Controller will provide, to the subject holding parental authority or to the legal guardian, requests concerning the personal data of minors.
4. Aims of the processing and purposes of technical session cookies.
The data provided voluntarily by users of the website is processed for the following purposes:
to respond to the request for offer and information from the user
to subscribe to the newsletter
to process statistics anonymously
subject to explicit user consent, to perform direct marketing and/or profiling activities with automated tools
to comply with legal obligations and with the provisions of the competent Authorities.
5. Mode of expression of consent
The consent to the processing of personal data through non-technical cookies can be expressed by clicking on a specific box contained within a banner.
6.Mode of processing and retention
The processing will be carried out in an automated and/or manual mode, with methods and tools, in compliance with the security measures set forth in art. 32 of the GDPR 2016/679 and in Italian Legislative Decree 196/2003, by specifically authorised subjects, in compliance with the provisions of art. 29 of the GDPR 2016/679.
In compliance with the principles of lawfulness, purpose limitation and data minimisation, pursuant to art. 5 of the GDPR 2016/679, the retention period of personal data is established for a period of time not exceeding the achievement of the purposes for which it is collected and processed and in compliance with the times prescribed by law and, however, as long as the interested party decides not to cancel the services offered by the data controller.
7. Retention period of personal data
The personal data processed and stored for all the purposes referred to in this statement is processed and stored for a period not exceeding 12 months starting from the date of the individual collection; the Data Controller reserves the right, in any case, to request that the interested party renews their consent to the processing and/or verifies the consents already expressed.
8. Place of processing
Personal data will be processed at the legal and operational headquarters of the Data Controller
9. Communication and dissemination of personal data
Personal data may be communicated to:
Couriers, shippers or third parties in charge of any packaging, shipping and/or delivery of any material requested through the website;
Companies, consultants, professionals, natural/legal persons, if communication is necessary or functional to the correct fulfilment of contractual obligations assumed as well as of the legal requirements.
Companies that offer information company services, including, in particular, those that offer hosting services.
All those subjects who have access to personal data under regulatory or administrative provisions.
No personal data will be processed without the user’s prior consent.
10. Data transfer
The Data Controller does not transfer data to third countries
11.Revocation of consent
With reference to art. 23 of Legislative Decree 196/2003 and to art. 6 of the GDPR 679/2016, the interested party can withdraw their consent at any time.
12. Rights of the interested party
At any time the user may exercise, pursuant to art. 7 of the privacy code and to arts 15-22 of the GDPR 2016/67, the right to:
a. Request confirmation of the existence or not of personal data;
b. Obtain information regarding the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data, the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the data was or will be communicated and, when possible, the retention period;
c. Obtain data correction and deletion;
d. Obtain processing limitation;
e. Obtain data portability, i.e. to receive it from a data controller, in a structure format, commonly used and readable by an automatic device, and to transmit it to another data controller without hindrance;
f. Oppose the processing any time and also in the case of processing for direct marketing and/or profiling purposes;
g. Oppose an automated decision-making process concerning individuals, including profiling;
h. Right to propose a complaint to the relevant Supervisory Authority.
The user may exercise their rights by writing to the Data Controller at the following address:
CDR srl, with headquarters at Via degli Artigiani, 6 – Ginestra Fiorentina – 50055 Lastra a Signa (Florence)
Telephone: +39 055 871 431
Fax: +39 055871422 E-mail: privacy@cdr-mediared.it
Modifications to this Privacy Policy
The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy disclosure at any time by giving notice to Users on this page. Please, therefore, consult this page often, using as a reference the date of last modification indicated at the bottom.
Privacy Information – Art. 13 of EU Regulation 679/2016
Last update: 21.05.2020
Request a Free Quote Now!
-- Select country -- *
Afghanistan
Albania
Algeria
American Samoa
Andorra
Angola
Anguilla
Ethiopia
Falkland Islands (Malvinas)
Faroe Islands
Fiji
Finland
France
French Guiana
French Polynesia
French Southern Territories
Gabon
Heard Island and Mcdonald Islands
Holy See (Vatican City State)
Honduras
Hong Kong
Hungary
Iceland
India
Indonesia
Iran, Islamic Republic of
Iraq
Virgin Islands, British
Virgin Islands, U.s.
Wallis and Futuna
Western Sahara
Yemen
Zambia
Zimbabwe
-- Select state
-- *
Alabama
CDR BeerLab® for Beer and Wort
* I accept privacy policy and authorize CDR s.r.l. to contact me to respond to my request for commercial information
With the CDR system, you can perform your tests in total autonomy Neither skilled staff nor a dedicated external laboratory is needed to use our systems. CDR FoodLab® optimizes
traditional testing methods, making them faster and easier, while guaranteeing accuracy standards in line with
the reference methods.
Analytical kit
CDR FoodLab® Analysis Systems use disposable pre-vialed reagents specifically developed by the research
laboratories of CDR. The use of pre-vialed reagents and the analytical procedures allow:
a sample preparation that is quick and easy, when needed at all;
making analytical procedures extremely fast and easy;
removing all needs for complex calibration procedures.
Reagents come in aluminum packages containing
10 test tubes each to perform 10 tests (or packages for 100
tests containing 10 single packages of 10 test tubes each).
Just a few steps and results are yielded right away Just a few steps will suffice to carry out your analysis in a rapid way in total autonomy. The system is composed
of both the analyzer based on photometric technology and a kit of low toxicity, pre-vialed reagents, developed by
CDR.
CDR FoodLab® is cost-effective because it does not require the use of expensive equipment and does not
entail maintenance, assistance or calibration costs.
Falkland Islands (Malvinas)
Holy See (Vatican City State)
Virgin Islands, U.s.
* I accept privacy policy and authorize CDR s.r.l. to contact me to respond to my request for commercial information
